Debasish Samal

Email: dssamal01@gmail.com

Contact no.: 9971072150 **Passport No.: R7555945 Valid Thru. : 06/05/28**S.D. Hospital campus,

Rourkela, Sundergarh, odisha

769004

Operation co-ordinater including (electrical Eng. With 5 + years of experience in Maintenance, Process Eng. and Projects). A passionate and forward-thinking professional having knowledge and experience in wide range of business function that would allow making positive impact.

Expertise Area:

- Maintenance, Engineering, & project management.
- Manufacturing
- •Organizational skills and team building.
- Problem solving.
- Quality management.
- Delegation management.
- Health and Safety procedures.
- Defect reduction
- Continuous improvement.
- Skill development.
- Problem Solving.

Core competencies:

- Manpower management.
- Injection molding(up to 1300 ton) & various types of SPM maintenance
- Li-Ion mobile & electric vehicle batteries. Wire harness
- Automobile Industries
- Preventive & Predictive Maintenance
- BIS, Kaizen, Kanban System
- Manpower & Cost saving.
- Defect reduction
- OEE, TPM, Productivity improvement.

Professional Experience:

Trumec India. Sanand, Ahmedabad, Gujarat: Operation Co-ordinater. (Sept.2022 to till date)

Trumec India is manufacturer of injection & blow molding tools, various SPMs (customized), Jigs & fixtures, etc.

Managing day-to-day project activities like marketing, Sales, Project progress, CSR follow ups, Upcoming project plans, etc.

- Currently looking after existing & upcoming projects (manufacturing, procurement etc.)
- Planning & leading Process guidelines of machines & Process, along with cycle time & new machines qualifications.
- Leading for auditing of line for customer & 5S' and correcting the observations.

TDK Navitasys India Pvt. Ltd. formerly Epcose India Pvt. Ltd. (Bawal): Process Engineer (March 2019 to August 2020)

Leading Company in India in manufacturing of Cell (Mobile & Electric Vehicle) batteries.

TDK is a globally leading Company in electronics components manufacturer & Robotics, headquarters in Japan.

Navitasys power is a subsidiary company of TDK Group.

- Managing day-to-day activities like assembly lay out, Process design, poka yoka design & review, process flow diagram, ECN, control plan, & Production requirements.
- Currently looking after existing & upcoming projects (Both installation & productivity)
 Planning & leading Process Capability Study (CPK) of machines & Process, along with cycle time & new machines qualifications

Accomplishments:

Executed Manpower saving in purchase cost of approx.19.5 Lacs.

- •A good team builder & motivator.
- •Implementation of animated work instructions thereby bringing clarity on setup change to ensure safety and reducing ambiguity.
- Adjudged best outsourcing team.
- •Reduction in defect cost from 0.23% to 0.18% and increase in tool life by 17%.
- •CPK & PPK improvements.

Certifications:

- Problem Solving.
- 5' S,
- Firefighting and first aid.

Extracurricular activities:

- Governor's award in Bharat scout & Guide
- •Volunteered for medical relief camp., NSS, Blood donation camp
 - Plant first aider.

Education:

- MBA(Operation& Marketing) –
 MDU Rohtak (BIMT, Gurugram) (2020-2022)Full time
- B Sc.(2018)
- Diploma Electrical Eng.(SCTE & VT odisha) (2012-2015)
- 12th (PCMB) (2012)

 Leading for auditing of line for customer & 5S' and correcting the observations

Knowledge of problem solving (4M method & by fishbone)

SANHO INDIA LTD. (Gurugram, Haryana) Maintenance department (June 2015 to March 2019)

Certified with ISO-9001-9002, TS 16949, and IATF 16949-2016 and Globally Leading in Brakes & fuel Pipe supply, is a subsidiary company of Sanho Japan.

- Handling all type Breakdown of SPM Machines (PLC Based Fully Automated), Conveyer Line, Heating unit, Leak test unit, & Assembly line in Shop floor.
- Moldings unit Maintenance along with HRTCs & MTCs.
- Planning & implementing new projects.
- Responsible for Kaizen improvement projects.
- Planning & Implement of Predictive & Preventive Maintenance of Machine.
- Responsible for trouble shooting the problem of machine.
- Preparing various maintenance reports.
- Responsible for Maintenance Tree, problem solving by fishbone diagram along with horizontal development.
- Responsibility of manpower planning for the Associates.